Arie Stapleton from Associated Press.
George, last night you said that your
two picks in the fourth round would
define the draft. So, what can you tell
us about Coleman and Casey and what you
envisioned for them?
>> Can you answer that? I'm sorry.
>> We're still in free agency. And so, um,
yeah, I think, um,
look, as you, as you go through the the
reads on the runners, for instance, um,
both Jonah and then, um, there was one
other back that, you know, we we kept
thinking
they were graded
early in the third, end of the second,
you know, are they that's that it's it
was the tough scenario. Will they will
they make it to 108? Um
it helped they were both
available because we had discussed even
climbing back. Um so Jonah has come in
for a visit. Um we spent a lot of time
with him. Um, I I I saw something that
compared his running style and and I
think the comparison was JK and I I
think that uh is a compliment obviously
to to the way Dobbins runs and um he's a
physical runner. Um so we were real
familiar with him and then Cage was
someone the same way. you know, how is
how does the league value, you know, the
guard swing tackle versus the running
back when we're deciding that order
because I think there were three picks
between and um and again the versatility
there um with Cage was was real
attractive. Um so that
that's a long wait, you know, if you
will, where you're going through um a
lot of picks. Um certainly we discussed
traveling back and and we ended up
fortunately, you know, staying put. So
um a lot of time I felt like a lot of
time went off between uh the beginning
today and then, you know, getting to
both Jonah and Cage. Sean, then you came
back up to get to get Jo Lee. You
mentioned before in the pre-draft call
just about sort of like there's
different types of tight ends.
>> Yeah. And I think this would be I'm
going to kind of hit really both tight
ends. Um you know with Bentley there's a
more inline Y bigger. Um he he does a
great job down the field. Um with with
Jolie um I would put them more in the F
category. Um both both are tight ends.
Um, and both have unique skill sets, so
they're they're different.
>> George, how much are those end of draft
picks kind of able to get the the
college free agents that you want? And
then how much are you recruiting over
this period of time to kind of sell in
the program as you talk about?
>> Well, I think that goes way back, I
mean, to the fall, you know, all-star
games. I'm talking about the recruiter,
you know, just as you get to know our
scouts are getting to know these
players, you know, that the um whether
they're going to be drafted or college
free agents. It's it's hard to to get a
u high-end college free agent unless you
have a relationship with them. So, that
goes with the coaches, that goes with
the scouts, you know, it's it's
everyone, you know, all hands on deck.
And so, um you know, when you get to the
last two picks, it's it's tough because
obviously you have college free agents
and then and so um everyone wants to be
drafted, they can. And so, we just kind
of work through that. You just kind of
follow your board at the end.
>> Sean, you already talked about uh Don
Bentley, but can you both talk about the
other two seventh round picks, Miles
Scott and Red Murdoch, your vision for
them, and especially Red's ability to
make plays?
>> Yeah, Miles we were real familiar with.
Um, you know, talking with Pao and Pat,
these guys were teammates and Illinois
had a handful of players, I think,
drafted. So, it would be very normal,
especially when a player's younger on
our roster and has been on the same team
and um you know, his name came up and
up, you know, he went in with Pat as a
receiver and then was converted. So,
with with both our players um his name
came up a number of times. Um
throughout the process, I think we
became very familiar with him. Um so,
there's versatility. uh special teams
flex. Um
>> yeah, I mean with with Miles I think you
know the ball skills I mean I think he
had seven interceptions throughout his
career and very physical for a former
receiver and instincts you know for a
guy who hadn't played it all that long.
We thought he really good anticipation
and instincts and thus you know he had
the interception. So thinks he he fits
in with our group and what we look for,
you know, in safeties. And then um
Murdoch, you know, just um man, he's a
tackling machine. Really instinctive. Um
really good verse the run. He may hold
the record, you guys may know, for force
fumbles. I think he had um everyone
talked about the Texas Tech guy and he
was amazing but this guy oh my gosh you
know if you look at his career and all
the force fumbles he had but just a nose
for the ball relentless motor think he
can be a good special teamer um no so we
like you know and great makeup you know
all these guys I think you know have
great makeup
>> it was unique
I think we said it during the draft like
the rest of your career no one in this
draft room will be a part of a draft
where you have the last two picks of the
draft And so all of that factoring in
with the free agents. Um there's eight
minutes where you're really
um kind of controlling everything and
and uh you there were a handful of
teams, believe it or not, that had
called about coming to get Mr.
Irrelevant for whatever reason or not.
So um
>> that was a hot pick.
>> Yeah.
>> For whatever. Um but no, that was um
and we kind of when we went through all
the mocks, we knew it would be a little
bit
um not only advantageous, but it gives
you eight minutes to kind of breathe
instead of four and evaluate where
you're at with other players. Um, and
both these guys had,
it's hard to, it's hard to project what
the dispersion looks like, you know,
when you get to that point in the draft
and and it worked out well.
>> Uh, Chris Thomas and Denver Gazette
George, since you touched upon Mr.
Relevant being a hot pick, what do you
how do you feel about that concept
that's been going on for 50 years,
bringing him out to Newport Beach and
all that, and how do you feel about
having Mr. Relevant now of your own?
>> I feel great. you know, we were just
trying to decide who
we should who would be better to go to
Balo Island or wherever Newport Beach,
you know, for these two. And and um I
mean, it's it's cool. I mean, it's I
think in my career, we've drafted two
and if I'm not mistaken, they both made
it, you know, and so um I'm not even
sure what it all entails, you know. I
think is it Newport Beach? Is it is
there a parade? Is and Patrick Smite has
to go apparently.
Maybe maybe the head coach.
>> Yeah. No, he he But listen, when we
talked to Bentley, he's vice president,
Mr. Irrelevant. So, if there's anything
that Murdoch can't handle, then the two
of them um
>> think they're going to fly them both.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh Sean, with with uh Jonah Coleman, how
much are you looking for when you're
evaluating these guys the the vision of
how quickly they could like have those
third down traits and and potentially
fill that role?
>> Great question. Um,
so we felt like, and every team's
different, we we felt like, you know,
certainly, you know, the front of the
draft, there were two really good
players, both uniquely both from Notre
Dame. Um, and then when you start
putting up
tail of the tape, I'm not talking about
their measurables, but I'm, you know,
the the four box production, yards after
contact, um, average 10 yards runs, all
those things you get to see on tape. Um,
and I would say probably
with a number of teams there may have
been six. and then what's you know
what's the order when you get to let's
say three four five six um but
you know going home yesterday coming in
today and then the long wait um I think
the thing that I would say is he's very
physical um
he he can play on third down and
normally you got to project that a lot
of these guys in college um maybe the
protection ction plan's different or
limited and so you have to develop that
and that's fine. Um but his frame is
such um when you when you see him u that
he does a he does a really good job in
in blocking pressure looks um he's
smart, he's tough there. There was a lot
to like with him.
>> You're right. I'm just for both of you.
When you have an established depth
chart, is it harder to sell undrafteds
and do you sell the developmental side
of it or how do how do you frame it?
I well I think challenge one would be
when you draft someone
and they you know you know this weekend
um oftent times uh that can be something
that might discourage a player. Um and
then yeah, there's certain positions
that um
you know, we always sell, man, pay
attention to the roster. Then we also
sell our program and our history with
these guys. Um, but I think when we go
into even
weeks back, like we know when the
draft's ending, these are going to be a
little bit challenging or more
challenging, you know, when it comes to
free agency and then there, holy cow,
that there are other positions where,
you know, we feel like we should have an
upper hand. Um, but often times it's
predicated on how that draft goes
>> and it can be challenging when you have
the last two picks in the draft.
>> That's challenging. Yeah, as you can see
by
>> Why aren't you drafting me? and and
yeah,
>> this did seem strategic the way you you
know addressed defense
I guess yesterday and then today you
really jumped out and it was it was all
offenses off offense. Is that the way
you saw the board, you know, a month
ago, two months ago that it would work
out this way?
>> No. No,
>> not even it.
>> Yeah. No, George has it. It was it was
>> I wish we we were that good at
forecasting. Um
the you know we just and I hate saying
the best player, you know, but um they
we just kind of took the best players as
they came and and sometimes need and the
best player intersected and it worked
out and but no, Mike, it it just kind of
worked out that way. You know, defense
yesterday then we had three straight
offense and then you know then two more
defense. So an off so just kind of
worked out that way. I mean, if you ran
a hundred of our scenarios that we
discussed, um, that earlier pick was at
other positions, um, you know, the next
morning,
it was that would have been hard. Like,
we had an idea who might be there at at
that first pick, but it was both
offensively and defensively, and that
was the hard part. Um,
>> yeah,
>> for either of you, I know you've been
asked about B a lot. There was some
reporting this afternoon that he had
gone back and seen Dr. Waldrip and all
that. Just is he sort of in the same
He's on the same track to be
>> He had a recheck that was scheduled. Um
he's doing great. Um man, he's we're
excited about his progress. Nothing
nothing to report. You know, these guys
will be coming in here. He's here.
Number of these guys are, you know, are
coming in the building. Um guys will be
working out Monday and then kind of
probably more of a team meeting next
week. Um and then certainly you've seen
the schedule
probably in the prior two years we would
have been out on the field and you guys
would have been out there with us you
know in May and it's it's kicked back a
little. So that'll take place in June.
>> Andrew Mason, Denver sports for both of
you guys with Justin and Jonah. Justin
has a low drop rate. Jonah has a low
fumble rate. When you're evaluating
receivers, running backs, tight ends,
how important is ball security when
you're kind of looking at the picture
and can you is that something you can
coach up into a player as a pro?
>> It's a great question. So, we were
looking at a player we we were
considering drafting last year and
historically speaking, um, we looked at,
let's just say, runners that were, you
know, maybe I had a high fumble rate.
Um, and then historically speaking,
they're drafted and history tells you
that can be cleaned up and corrected.
Um, and we were comparing it versus
another stat where history wasn't so
kind. Um, but yes, I I think when you
watch ball security at any position or
ball disruption and it takes an athlete
who's talented and then you also see how
they're being coached and uh and so it's
that combination, but um
it certainly makes the decision easier
if they're not uh if if if they're
having trouble with it. But when it
comes to ball security, um, that's
something and that was a 20-year study
that we just went back, you find us
fumblers that became NFL players, good
NFL players that didn't turn it over as
much. And Absolutely.
>> Going back to Miles in the seventh
round, uh, for him, he he comes up, he
makes a lot of plays, 150 different solo
tackles. When you guys are evaluating a
receiver to a DB switch, how much does
that factor into how much they can grow
inside your system, even if they don't
have all the traits that maybe a more
refined guy will have?
>> I I think the exposure initially is the
the interesting thing is this guy's if
if I were to tell you was which one of
the safeties was the receiver, I don't
know that you would have selected this
player. Um, and it's us it's usually
the second piece of information as
you're watching film. We we always ask
that question. High school sports, you
know, this year we had a we had more
baseball players, which was kind of
refreshing. Um wrestlers
>> making a comeback. Baseball.
>> Yeah, it's good.
>> Um and then a little bit more intimately
with with Palo and um Pat. We got, you
know, a lot more history. He's from
Dalton, Illinois. Um but I I it's funny.
you don't feel like you're seeing a
receiver conversion. And to your
question or to your question initially,
I think that um you look at time at the
position, uh there were a few players
that we looked at in this draft and we
said, "Look, they're in year two of
maybe an entirely different position."
And
so that's encouraging when you're when
you're studying their growth potential.
Uh Sean, you've talked about it being
difficult to kind of feature three three
runners at at certain times. In part,
did you like Coleman because maybe the
complimentary traits to what you had in
in the room? What's what's the thinking
there?
>> Yeah, I I think it still gets back to
what George said earlier. Um,
we're not getting too cute here with the
man, we're trying to find like
who's the who's the best runner and does
it fit us. Um, we felt strongly it did
with him. Um, and then all the other
stuff will take care of itself. Um,
but he he's he's put together his his
you know that position. There's some
positions that are more difficult and I
think this position is like, man, let's
just go look at it. What kind of scheme
are they running? Um, it was impressive.
>> Uh, for both of you guys, uh, just now
that the draft is over, how do you feel
kind of overall about what you guys were
able to accomplish over the last couple
days as well as just how you feel about
the state of your team right now?
No, I think we both feel really good
about the last, you know, couple days
and and in and the team in general and,
you know, I talked about it last night.
You know, we had seven picks that we had
seven total picks and yet, you know, we
also got waddle, you know, and and uh
and so feel good about the team, feel
good about the weekend. You know, I I
think we helped our depth. We helped our
team in a lot of areas. You know, we
wanted to get younger in both lines. I
felt like we did that and, you know,
wanted to get some, you know, some
offensive help as well. you know, it's
more explosion and I we helped ourselves
at running back and tight end and and
just depth across the board and so I
think we got younger. Um I think we got
better over the weekend and then you
factor in, you know, our first round
pick is is a really good player. So feel
good about that as a whole and we got
great makeup. I think all these you go
down the list, there's captains, you
know, on this list and and I could go
through each of these players and and
so, you know, we just added to a really
good locker room. Coach. Hey. Kardio 13
in Colorado Springs. Um, you talked
about the spray, you know, shorter in
the first round or two and then gets
wider and wider. How fun was it to kind
of deal with that larger spray in rounds
three through seven? Obviously, it's a
challenge, but you know, at the end of
seven rounds, you guys cover this makes
sense. Um, and I'm going to age myself a
little. Um, internet was what, 2008?
20 like when did we ditch the
Blackberries? Um
I it was somewhere I know when we back
in ' 06 it was just the blackberries and
then you'd have you know a few guides
you know our lads or and um
and now we're here we are in 2026 and
you know Bill used to always say 95%
of the discussion relative to the
coverage is around you know call it 17th
of the draft.
And so it's covered so well now. And I
think if you went back to pre- internet
and and you were just, you know, there
were a few books, there were television
shows, um you would have seen maybe a
little bit of a broader dispersion rate
in the first round. Um, and we were
watching the draft last night and you
know there's let's say 18 19 players off
the board and and um who's going to be
the first one that's just you know
outside the norm and um and then look a
team like the Rams make a decision and
and you know and and so well just
envision then you get into
second, third and it just changes
drastically um where teams see players
and um and it's it's not because of the
internet, it's just as you continue to
look and value players 79 or 84 um it it
drastically changes. So every year you
you know you're you're hoping as a team
players to the right of your board are
getting taken to your left and pushing
players that you want. You know, you're
hoping that's happening um happening
throughout the draft and um so it it you
know that that's been pretty constant um
compared to maybe uh years ago. I mean
they they gathered in a basement when
there were nine owners and I I mean
there were teen rounds. We were reading
we had we had some time today. So
>> five to seven is I mean I don't know how
long that was. It was
>> so we we read three hours
>> you know who's top seventh pick of all
time you know and and there were seven
or eight Hall of Famers. Sixth round was
easy. um fifth round and then someone in
the room was filling filling us in on
19th round or third, you know, I can
remember when I was in college, I think
there were 13 rounds. Um so
it it's certainly come a long way.